In a country where financial security is
still a new conversation, Vietnam now
stands at a turning point. A young
population is entering the workforce
with more income than ever before. Yet,
beneath the promise of growth lies a
quiet challenge. An aging society,
retirement gaps, and a lack of financial
literacy. To solve this problem, in this
episode, we will explore the future of
financial protection and investment in
Vietnam. With three leaders of
Prudential Vietnam. Together, they share
their vision of peace of mind for every
Vietnamese family and how to build
trust, adapt to a rising middle class,
and meet the expectations of Gen Z. They
also reveal how protection, investment,
and digital are coming together to shape
Vietnam's financial future.
Welcome to this very special episode of
the Vietnam Innovators podcast. Uh for
those of you that don't know, I'm the
host of that program. My name is Hal.
Today, we have a very special lineup of
guests. Uh we have three leaders of
Prudential Vietnam, uh one of the
leading insurers here in Vietnam. Um I
have many friends that work at
Prudential and they've told me about the
family, the community of Prudential. And
so, I actually wanted to test Kevin cuz
he's he's a bit new to Prudential. So, I
asked him for a pin. So, if you look at
my jacket right here, I I have the
Prudence pin. And I now have a photo of
him giving me the pin. So, make sure you
ask him for that pin as well. Uh very
generous. Thank you, Kevin. Sure.
[Music]
[Applause]
So, today, everyone, as the whole event
has been centered around this new
product launched by Prudential, uh we
want to theme today's conversation
around the future of financial
protection and investment in Vietnam. Uh
there's a lot of young people entering
the workforce. Uh they have more income
than ever and they're looking about how
to diversify their assets, how to invest
for the future. So, we have three
experts who will be sharing that with us
today. Um Kevin, I'm going to start with
you.
I think you're one of the newest on the
block here, although maybe Manish
you you are? Marginally.
>> Marginally. So, I'm going to start with
you, straight to you. Um Prudential
Vietnam has a new mission, uh a new
refreshed mission of we provide peace of
mind to every Vietnamese family. So,
from your perspective as the CEO, what
are the key forces that will shape the
future of financial protection in
Vietnam over the next 10 years? Thanks,
Hal, for asking a very good question. I
think right now, if we look at the
market in Vietnam, we're in a very
critical juncture. So, for us to take
this industry to the next level,
there will be multiple forces.
And there's no right or wrong answers.
This is this my personal belief.
I think number one, uh is as I said, to
restoring the confidence and trust from
the customer has to be number one.
Because of what has happened in the
market in the last 3 4 years. To me,
there's a simple equation.
Trust equals to
sales quality and service quality.
When these two are multiplied,
the impact on increasing trust
amplifies. So, we are very committed in
in driving this.
Um at the same time, to make this
working, the regulator plays a very
critical role.
And
lately, as you can see, uh I believe MOF
and ISA have make have taken some bold
moves and changes in the regulation.
I think that is really right direction.
So, what we want to do is to piggyback
right on that change that we're making
at the regulator level
to drive what is is necessary for us to
improve the sales quality and the
service quality.
And we really hope that other industry
players will take part in this journey
together with Prudential. So, that'll be
the first uh force I think that'll be
critically important. The second one
would be then the uh
being more innovative in terms of coming
up with the right proposition for our
customers. Cuz ultimately, we need to
help uh Vietnamese families to close the
protection gap. The as the wealth goes
up, the protection gap actually widens.
And it is our responsibility to provide
the offerings that make sense for
families of Vietnam to really help them
to close that gap, whether it be the
health gap, retirement gap, uh mortality
gap. So, that innovation will be
important. Uh and to make it simple as
well.
And the third part would be uh probably
using the digital.
Uh digital transformation, a lot of
people talk about it, but it's really
about how to use that technology to help
our customers and employees to make
their decisions making easier.
And uh it is something that we are very
passionate about at Prudential. Uh to
make this as part of become our daily
practice. So, that will be another uh
important force to reshape this
industry. The last one would be, you
know, when people think of health, most
of people think of physical health. But
also, there is other elements as well.
Uh having a uh mental clarity and having
a balanced emotion. So, all these things
combined together is something that we
as a Prudential would like to offer as
our proposition to our customers with
aim to give, you know, the uh to provide
the peace of mind to all Vietnamese uh
Vietnamese families here. So, Kevin,
thank you for sharing. And as I
understand, you've worked all across the
region and you've seen different
challenges and opportunities in other
markets. And that's potentially brought
a new sense of innovation, fresh
perspective in your role as the CEO of
Prudential. So, my question for you
would be do you see Vietnam as facing a
different set of financial protection
challenges compared with other Asian
markets? Or is it fairly similar? Would
love to hear your insight on that. I
think the problem that um
or the challenge that Vietnam sees uh
probably more or less same as what you
see in other neighboring countries, too.
The only difference is the the magnitude
uh of the challenge that we're faced
with. So, point in case, protection gap
is quite big in Vietnam. So, but you see
in even developed countries like
Singapore, Hong Kong, they also have the
same protection gap.
Uh it just happens that we have a wider
gap to catch on. So, uh it's the same
responsibility and same challenges that
we're faced with. It's about how
effectively do we shape up our industry
together
uh to help to close that gap. Okay, very
good. And and one last question for
Kevin before we move over to Connor. I
can see him very eager.
>> questions in a row. I know, three
questions. You're the CEO. So, we we see
this clear shift towards these solutions
such as digital, you mentioned,
integrating everything, protection,
investment, all in one. How do you see
this trend shaping customer
expectations?
Um and how do you believe that
Prudential will be the one delivering
that peace of mind?
I think the customers and consumers'
expectations will ever increase.
And especially with the help of
technology, with the help of uh the
information accessibility to
information, then what's also important
is to help the customers increase the uh
the awareness
of the financial literacy. I think
that's another responsibility that we
Prudential as a sees
uh as an investment that we need to
make. So, it's not really about always
giving the best protection, but it's
also helping the society to increase
that awareness together.
So, when that awareness goes up, and
then the access to information
increases, and the ability to be able to
provide the right solutions to
customers, then I think it could be a
really win-win situation for everybody,
which can really should reshape and grow
the industry together.
Very good. Um we're going to move over
to the CFO of Prudential Vietnam,
Connor. Um Connor, Prudential is one of
the biggest British investors in
Vietnam, but I would say also investors
in general. It's been a very long, rich
history in the country. Um how would you
say that this long-term capital
commitment reflects confidence in the
growth story over the years to come?
Okay. Uh thanks for the question. Um
I suppose when when you look at
long-term commitment, you want to make
sure you're committing yourself to
someone
who's going to stay with you and stay
with you for a long time.
Um a bit like your pin, which you just
got today, your Prudence will be here
for a long time.
Uh as a group, we've been around for 175
years. And beyond that, we're within
Vietnam, we've been here for 25 years.
Prudential in Vietnam, it's a must-win
market for Prudential. We're one of the
top five markets within the group.
And we've invested into the company
here to make sure that we're we're here
for the long term. We've got over 1
billion US dollars of investment, 27
trillion dong invested into the company
here. Um
why have we done that? Cuz we believe in
the long term of the country. We believe
in the long term
uh
protection gap and investment gap that
we can fulfill
uh and um help the country close that
gap. The key thing behind that is in is
the premiums coming in and the
investments from our customers and how
we invest them back into the economy.
So, of our invested assets of 27
trillion, on top of that, our customers
have given us another 170 trillion. So,
we've almost got 200 trillion
8 billion US dollars of investments in
the country, which are all invested with
our friends at Eastspring, our M Chai,
our little brother within the group on
our behalf. And when we look like a look
at a product
like we're launching today,
the key elements of this is all these
premiums are going to be invested into
the future of Vietnam. If you think back
to 2000, when the stock exchange opened
in in Ho Chi Minh, there were two
companies.
Now there's 1,600
companies to invest in in the stock
market.
With Resolution 68,
the focus of the investment that the
country's going to need to make into
uh SMEs and emerging businesses to
become worldwide players, there's a
ready tap market
that we want our customers to have
access to, not just in the securities uh
on the stock exchange, but also
corporate debt and infrastructure. So we
see very much our commitment long-term
being an investment of our customers'
money back into Vietnam to help Vietnam.
And that's a commitment that we're
making as a group.
Um as I said, it's
the opportunity here to fill that gap is
uh from behalf of our customers is
enormous and we're here for the long
term. So as a group that's been around
for 175-plus years, here for 25, we
think long long term and so therefore we
believe we're the right partner to be
committed to. All the stories of
Prudential the last 25 years, a lot of
rich history with the country.
Let's keep it up. We will try. Thank you
so much, Connor.
[Music]
[Applause]
Uh as we move over to our next segment,
which is about customer needs and growth
challenges. Uh I know that the agents in
the room are really eager to hear about
this because they need and want new
innovative products for their customers
and I think the team here is eager to
share about the first of many
uh in the years to come here. So
Manisha, over to you.
Uh Vietnam's growing middle class is
growing rapidly.
Uh priorities are now around education,
retirement, long-term financial
security.
How are customer needs shifting in your
view and how is Prudential Vietnam
adapting its strategy right now to meet
those needs? Let me start with some data
points. There are some telling uh data
points and just talks about the
opportunity uh also referring to what
Connor said on on the country potential.
So
13% of the population was middle class
in 2023. That's doubled in 2026 to 26%.
That's going to almost double to 55%
in 2030. Every 3 to 5 years,
the middle class population is almost
doubling. And if you put that in context
of numbers, about 50 million potential
middle class customers in Vietnam in
about 5 years' time. As this shift
happens,
we're going to see roughly 8 to 10%
growth in disposable income every year.
And with that growth of disposable
income, consumption patterns, investment
patterns will change from spending on
just necessity,
we'll start to see spending on wellness,
lifestyle, future financial planning.
We're going to start to see a lot more
focus on planning for education
for the next generation,
lifestyle related changes, retirement,
and transfer of this wealth to the next
generation, something we refer to as
intergenerational wealth transfer. Now
this is a huge opportunity, but we still
see less than 10%. If you look at the
entire country's population, less than
10% are actually investing in financial
investment. And I don't mean having
banking accounts or deposit accounts,
that's that's different. Obviously the
penetration there is much higher.
But in actual investment products,
wealth investment, financial investment.
So there's still a large portion of this
investment that goes in traditional
assets like gold,
real estate.
And so we as Prudential and we as an
industry need to do our part to bring a
lot more people on this journey. And so
what we the launch of the product today
on the investment link is one of the
small steps from our side. Having the
right product for the right segment
through the right channel is important.
Having a diversified portfolio is
important and we feel this is one of the
key steps
towards really taking the customers on
that very important journey. Very good.
And I also wanted to share too um so I'm
a millennial,
older Gen Z, I'm 33 years old and
when I was starting to become an adult,
not too long ago, I guess, I remember
learning about my health, my financial
uh personal finance. And I remember like
15 years ago, it wasn't really
available. But the the velocity, the
speed of that information is now
becoming available. But I think it's up
to companies, the the stakeholders here
to help nurture that next generation too
cuz it's evolving so quickly. So um I'd
love to see more of that uh from all
partners and I think you guys are one of
the leaders in that. Keep it up. I want
to learn more.
So about customer needs, uh Vietnam does
face some structural challenges. For
example, aging population. I think
Korea, Japan, they kind of steal the
headlines a little bit, but let's not
forget Vietnam needs more babies.
Uh there's retirement gaps uh and like I
just said, financial literacy literacy
is in demand, but it is limited.
So from your view, how is Prudential
Vietnam positioning itself as a pioneer
to solve these critical national
priorities?
I actually see those as opportunities
from a corporate perspective.
Um you're right. I I
uh I I looked it up and I think median
age of Vietnam right now is surpassing
30.
Uh the birth rate not as high as it used
to be.
So the country is also aging. Probably
not at that pace yet, but it's getting
there.
So as a result then uh as the wealth
increases, uh the protection gap widens.
People aging. Definitely I think that's
a a place for a company like Prudential
to play in
in in helping them.
But again, as I said, um for us it's not
always about business. It's about
helping the society to kind of grow
and especially around the areas of
helping them to increase their financial
literacy.
We do have a program called Cha-Ching.
Have you heard of it? I have.
Not yet. Not Cha-Ching? Cha-Ching. Like
when you
>> Like Cha-Ching. Okay. Yeah. So this is
one of the strengths of Prudential. We
do have a Prudence Foundation.
And every year we do invest in the
society.
Uh whichever country we operate in, but
especially in Vietnam, we have done a
fantastic job. So Cha-Ching is the
program that's targeted for uh younger
Vietnamese
uh who are in the elementary school
mostly. So so far we've helped over
60,000 students uh with 2,000 teachers
across 372 schools uh across Vietnam. So
that's just one of uh many uh
initiatives that we drive together to
help to fight this challenge together,
but to really look at this as an
opportunity
uh more than anything. It just reminded
me offline I had a conversation with
Kevin about how his values are growing
with people. Uh he's he's growing with
people decades in his career.
And I think that's what we're sharing
here today. Prudential's been here 25
years. So from year one, you guys built
a platform. These products are very
long-term thinking. You grow with the
customers and if you're launching
something short-term, you're going to
break your customers' trust. So it's
great to hear that Prudential's values
are really got long-term foundation in
that regard. Uh as we adapt to customer
needs. Back to Manisha, what would you
say are some of the most surprising
or counterintuitive,
I guess, practices and behaviors you've
seen from Vietnamese customers. Uh I'd
love to hear your insights about that
and and to share with our agents here
Sure. Sure. Happy to help.
I mean the
technology and the role of technology
and AI
um
as much as it has evolved and you see so
much disruption happening in so many
sectors, it's going to change the way uh
future jobs are created. It's going to
change the way future industries are
born, right?
But the one thing about insurance that
we see, which may be counterintuitive to
some,
is
uh no matter how much ever, you know, we
move towards a digital lifestyle,
when it comes to financial planning,
when it comes to investing in
really important decisions 15, 20 years
in the future,
uh decisions
like investment or insurance, which are
meant to really protect,
preserve,
and pass on wealth to your uh to your
family,
people still want that human touch.
And uh we have yet to see a model which
is
fully robotic, fully AI-driven. It may
happen, you know, I I might be I might
be biting my fingers after a few years.
It may happen in the future. But as of
now, what we see in Vietnam, they want
the convenience
of a digital experience, but when it
comes to making a decision on some of
these important financial outcomes,
they definitely want the human touch.
So that's that's the first one I would
say. I I've got a couple of more, How,
if you don't mind, yeah. So
the second one I would say it's it's a
price conscious economy.
Yeah, as as most of the emerging
economies here in Southeast Asia.
But for life insurance,
flexibility, convenience, and having a
one-stop shop,
something that can combine protection,
investment, health, critical illness,
and having it all as one main product
that you can monitor, that you can
track, that you can keep an eye out on
still outweighs the point on just price.
Of course, price is important. We can't
be far away from competition, but if you
were to offer a proposition that
combines a lot of these in one,
customers don't put price as the first
criteria. They want to see this
flexibility. They want to see the
convenience. So, something that we're
doing today as well as part of a product
launch by looking at ILP, the the the
new product, you know, as a combination.
And the last one I would say on this,
when we talk about investment-linked
insurance plans,
normally you would think that customer
want the best returns. Of course, they
do.
But there's increasingly a segment of
customers
who are asking for,
"Where do you invest? Are you investing
in sustainable models? Are you investing
in building a green economy for my
country, for Vietnam?
What am I going to see not just in terms
of what I get back, but what the country
gets back, right? So, there is an
increasing sense and awareness of for
sustainability, for responsible
investment, for making us accountable
companies and citizens. So, I would say
those might be some of the
counterintuitive for a new person who
comes in into the industry. Yeah. I I
really like your first one. I like all
of them, actually, but your first one
reminds me, and I'll remind the
audience, was about that human touch.
Digital is so important about top of the
funnel, but to to convert, to nurture,
to support the customer, that human
touch is so important. Even in a very
simple terms, like calling a taxi on the
digital phone.
Everything is so automated. You know
exactly when they're arriving, but the
driver in Vietnam will always call you
to confirm. I think that's such a a a
good analogy to kind of mention what you
just
what you just said. People want
confirmation. They want that final human
touch, even though most of the process
is automated. Thank you, Manisha, for
sharing that.
[Music]
[Applause]
Connor, we're going over to you. Our
next section's going to be about
financial strength and trust. Uh we've
heard a lot from the Prudential team
about uh their insights about customer
needs, about why they're doing this, but
do they have the strength, and do they
have the trust to really hold up to what
they're sharing today? So, we're going
to question Connor here first. Um
By the way, I I I definitely believe it
is, but I'd love to hear from you first
hand, as does the audience.
Uh financial strength is the foundation
of any insurer. If you don't have cash
on hand, how can anyone work with you?
Uh so, how would you say that Prudential
is ensuring the strong capital base,
uh as well as disciplined risk
management, and stable investment
returns for your customers in Vietnam?
Tha- Thank you, D. Again, it's a it's an
interesting balancing act, but again,
I'll go back to my first answer. It's
something we've been doing for 175
years. So, as a group, we've got the
muscle memory,
uh and we've got the discipline from
other markets that we bring here. As I
said earlier, there was
we have that 1 billion of shareholder
assets within Vietnam, which is the most
of any insurance company has in the
marketplace, which is great. So, when
you look at the
solvency position of any company across
the market, we're amongst the top, if
not the top, for actual assets being
held. Also, the regulator seeks us to
keep a level of capital to manage the
risk that we run.
Um we've got that plus 100% more.
So, we've got double the capital
on our balance sheet than the regulator
believes that we need
um to to to manage and run the business.
But what does this mean day to day?
It means that
when a customer needs money, we can pay.
In some of the presentations you'll see
from us as a group, you'll understand
that one in four dong paid by the
industry year in, year out is from
Prudential. So, for every four claims
that come in, one will be dollars that's
paid out on time to our customer base.
That's a key element of the the trust
and the promise that Kevin touched about
earlier that we can do because we have
that strength. Uh we don't renege on our
promises. We don't renege on our our
policies.
And then when we switch the that element
back into the balance sheet, what do we
do with our assets? Well, again, we're
proud that all 190 billion of our
assets, uh trillion dong of our assets,
are invested with Eastspring. They are
using the same investment techniques and
research capabilities that we use across
the whole of the group.
The group's got assets over 250
billion US dollars
of asset, you know, covering US,
covering UK, covering Europe, covering
Hong Kong, covering um Singapore, and
the rest of the the the group's um
investment markets. We bring that same
discipline to Vietnam.
And uh
our friends at Eastspring will show um
presentations today that show how we've
taken that discipline over the last 17
years that we've written ILP here, and
we've outperformed the index. As I said,
as the market has gone from two funds to
1,600
individual stocks, no one customer, no
one person can cover all of that.
So, that's where you need the
investment expertise and the backbone
and and also the risk discipline
uh that you get from our compliance and
risk colleagues into what we invest and
how we invest. So, that capability has
been built up over many, many years, and
definitely we can see the fruition of
that. One in our number one, we pay our
claims, the one in four, but then also
the investment outperformance we're
seeing from our MGI at Eastspring is is
key to get to to give that comfort to
the customer, and we can see that over
the the period we've had with profits
funds in the last 17 years we've had for
our um
uh for our ILP funds. And it's something
that we're we treasure.
We don't take for granted, so we work
hard at it every day to make sure we
keep doing the right things year in,
year out into the future.
By the way, I have learned so much from
this podcast right now. Um
as I was researching, of course,
everyone knows Prudential. Who doesn't?
But Eastspring, which I'm very excited
to hear about in the presentation, by
the way. Um I was looking at how you
guys invest, and
even in places like Singapore and Hong
Kong, there's like Prudential financial
centers, like real estate. Um maybe not
now, but I'd love to know like what
actual investments you guys are making
because I think the it's just beginning.
You know, what you're sharing some
really exciting things that you're
doing, but I'm already thinking like,
"Will there be a Prudential financial
center?" You don't have to answer that
question, by the way. Um but a lot of
room for growth uh with the balance
sheet you guys have. So, really exciting
stuff.
Um over back to Manisha here. So, we
just talked about financial strength.
Let's talk about trust. Um the new wave
of customers that you were talking about
that are now of working age, they have a
little bit more disposable income, they
must be super top of mind for your team.
Fortunately, unfortunately, they're Gen
Z. Uh I think it's a double-edged sword.
I I work with a lot of them, um and and
they have trust issues, uh which is a an
opportunity, as as Kevin would say.
Uh so, Gen Z, for the audience, uh
they're up to 28 years old here in
Vietnam. What does building trust with
the Gen Z look like compared to older
customers? Would love to hear from you,
Manisha.
Yeah, I mean, um
the the topic of Gen Z always comes up,
right? When we are having discussions
like these, and um
uh and for some reason, when we when we
refer to Gen Z's, you know, we always
refer to it in a cautious, careful way,
you know, slightly raising our eyebrows,
and you know, how do we how do we deal
with them?
Honestly, you know, the way we look at
it, uh both in terms of staff, you know,
when they join us and when they work for
us,
it's uh super positive. It's super
exciting. It's super energizing.
They lift up the culture in the company.
They create so much energy, so much
vibrancy, and and youth
that it just makes the organization, you
know, much, much younger, right? In
terms of behavior and culture. So, I'm
personally a big fan. Um
But also in the context of when they buy
insurance, I think
their impatience
drives our innovation.
So, we really, really
uh
it may be tough to deal with at that
point of time, but the fact that they
want complete transparency,
complete accountability,
speed of service,
as well as personalization,
can you imagine in terms of if you're a
chief customer officer,
and you're trying to address that
segment, the kind of
changes you can bring into the
organization
to address those demands can only be
good for the company,
as long as you do it in a proper way,
and you know, managing the right
controls, and
being compliant, you know, from a
regulatory standpoint. So, all the
initiatives that we're having now,
whether it's using um speech to text,
whether it's using AI for our video
recording, cuz they want the
transparency, they want the records.
Or whether it's bringing in electronic
KYC now that we have the national ID or
whether it's building in chatbots, you
know, for servicing, personalization,
digital signatures, cashless claims, all
of the all of those changes, right, that
we're trying to build in are actually
only going to be positive and they're
coming in from a from, you know, from a
demand from from the younger and and and
the not-so-younger generation, but
they're all the right things. I think
the second thing I would say is uh
they are definitely unique in the sense
of how they look at companies and
brands.
They really want to know the purpose.
They really want to know who you stand
for. What are the values? What's your
mission? And they really really want to
connect to that at a deeper level.
You can't just say we're we're we're an
insurance product.
What do you stand for? What are you
doing for the community? What are you
doing for the society? So, they're
really demanding in that aspect, right?
They want you to walk the talk.
And again, they demand focus on
sustainability, inclusivity, right? So,
the focal the fact that we have one of
one of the pooling funds that we spoke
about is focused on sustainability and
ESG. It appeals a lot to them cuz we can
talk about giving back to the community.
So, I would say those are some of the
unique characteristics, but none that
are
uh disturbing in any way. If anything,
it drives us to to a much more positive
place
and gets all the right uh strategy and
the right initiatives out in terms of
technology and investment. It reminded
me of what you just shared. What Gen Z
really care about these days is
with their time spent on mobile devices,
on social media platforms, it's almost
like every company is a media company
today, actually. So, how communication
events like this are are very important
for the stakeholders, but also to the
Gen Z. How do we communicate as
companies, as brands, as stakeholders
really important these days as well.
Thank you, Manish.
[Music]
[Applause]
Uh next and our last topic that we want
to cover today is about sustainability
and lifetime partnership. Uh we've
talked about this a little bit already.
Uh Prudential's been in the market for
25 years and they've built products
intentionally with that lifetime value
in mind. So, I'm going to kick it over
to Connor for the next question, which
is about sustainability and how it's at
the heart of financial leadership. So,
for you, Connor, um how is Prudential
aligning its investments in Vietnam with
its sustainable development goals? Uh
the government's been very clear about
its SDG objectives. I forget the exact
timeline, 2040, 2050. There There's
a milestone for everything.
Uh while at the same time securing
protection and returns for customers.
Um again, this is a very hot topic for
all insurance companies across the
world.
We believe that, you know, we're the the
asset owners on behalf of our customers
and insurance companies should reflect
society and should be investing where
society believes those investments
should go.
And as Manish said, you know, there's
there's a growing uh expectation that we
should be investing into sustainable
funds on behalf of our customer base.
And you can see that last year we
launched with the first life company to
launch a a sustainable fund, a green
future fund. Um and it kind of goes back
to the the element of doing well by
doing good.
You know, that fund has outstripped the
performance of the of the of the index
since it was launched in March last
year. Um so, there's definitely a a
thread that it
you don't have to give up any investment
return by investing into the right
assets. And that's something again if
they investment discipline for us is
very key that we we have that
discipline. It's not just investing in
any green asset, it's investing in the
right investments, the right companies
that have got the right um long-term
behaviors that we believe will give
those returns to our customers. The key
thing is for our products
especially today's product, they will
last 20, 30, 40 years.
And what we want to do is find
investments that will last 20, 30, 40
years. And we're looking real We're
working
um
with the IAV, with the with the
insurance regulator into how can we
invest into
you know, what I'd love to invest into
railways,
you know, linking Hanoi to Ho Chi Minh.
I'd like to invest in new highways. I'd
like to invest in uh faster technology
connectivity. I'd like to invest in new
ports. I'd like to invest in green
energy.
Those are long long-term commitments
that insurance companies should be
investing in um to support the society
that they represent. And that's where I
see we've got a a unique role to play on
behalf of our customer base to fulfill
that need.
And beyond that as a group,
um there's a partnership called the just
energy transition partnership, which is
seeking to invest 15 billion US dollars
into green energy in Vietnam. Um and
Prudential and Eastspring are the two
asset owners and asset managers, the
only two asset owner and asset manager
represented on that. Now, this isn't for
the funds for us as Prudential Vietnam.
I'm representing the rest of Prudential,
the rest of that 250 billion dollar
balance sheet to see are there
opportunities for Prudential to invest
into Vietnam to help build those roads
and bridges and railways,
IT connectivity, green energy. So,
that's something as a group that we're
looking at very seriously and promoting
because we believe it's the right thing
for the country as the right thing for
our policy holders, be they policy
holders in Vietnam or representatives of
our policy holders in other countries.
And that's where I think insurance
companies can make a huge difference.
And products like this
are the
unlock that capital
to improve society and help drive the
economy and the GDP growth as we go
forward.
I think a lot of companies are going to
be calling you after this, Connor.
They're going to they're going to be
asking for investment from Eastspring
after this.
Very good. Thank you so much. Kevin,
over to you. Uh you you mentioned
earlier that the last few years
um it's been a bit tough for the
industry, um but I must say you are a
man on a mission.
You are
determined to build trust, rebuild
trust, and strengthen in financial
services, specifically life insurance.
What does Prudential plan to do
differently in Vietnam to earn that
trust?
To answer that question, probably um
I need to go back to think about why
we exist, life insurance.
We're we're in the protection business,
which is a very noble business. We help
people.
There are not too many industries that
really go out and help people. We are
one of them.
For me, it's really about going back to
basic.
Um
stick to what we're good at and be
absolutely focused on
what is that we're supposed to do. As
Connor mentioned about our financial
strength, we're very strong because we
have been operating in this market for
26 years.
And they that gave us the scale.
The scale. We're in the scale business.
When we have that scale, we have the
ability to play and bet on some bold
move that others cannot.
So, for me, when I reflect on this
question,
it's really about boiling down to the
management team.
Do we have the right management team in
a company
that believes in certain purpose and
mission?
And does that cascade down to the
employees level?
So, when you have a group of people
within that organization that believes
in the mission the company has to
deliver,
it can create amazing things.
And I think that's what make Prudential
very different. Number one.
And number two, we're not in hurry.
We're not in hurry
because we already have that scale we
need.
What we're focused on is doing the right
thing
in the right way with the right people.
Why?
Only that will give the sustainability.
No shortcut.
Quality attracts quality.
And that's what we believe in it. That's
what my management team believes in it.
That's what our employees believes in
it. That's what our distribution
sales force believes in it.
Only when then
we can do the right thing for our
customers.
Only when then the customers will have
the trust
in life insurance, especially with
Prudential.
And to do that consistently, repeatedly,
and over and over,
we'll earn the trust from our customers.
I feel very proud to wear this pin. It's
only been 1 hour after what you just
shared, Kevin.
Spectacular.
Uh thank you so much.
Um
so, if there's any big takeaways from
that, everyone, uh Kevin and his team
definitely on a mission to build on this
trust
uh that they've built over the last 25,
26 years here. Thank you so much, Kevin.
Uh we just have a few questions left.
So, today we're at the new product
launch, but I'd like to each uh hear
from each of our uh team leaders here
about their perspective about what kind
of peace of mind will be offered to
Vietnamese customers by bringing this
product to market. So, we'll start with
Manish and then come down here. So,
Manish, over to you.
Yeah, thanks for that. I mean, I
mentioned before, right? One of the
counterintuitive, you know, insights, if
you would, is customers prefer a
one-stop shop.
Uh often
that outweighs, you know, just the price
point, right? As a stand-alone
parameter.
So, with this product, what we've tried
to do, offer a strong investment uh
model
while at the same time provide
protection for yourself, for your loved
ones
while giving you the opportunity to
deliver intergenerational wealth
transfer to the next generation.
All of these things combined in one
we feel will address
a varying set of customer needs
through one through one platform,
through one product. And I feel
that will give them the peace of mind.
Thank you, Manish. Conor, over to you.
That's great, Manish. You've taken up
three of the obvious topics of the of
the product. Um
for me
the peace of mind comes from you know
that every dong premium we receive in
will go into investment in the future of
Vietnam.
And that you're investing in the nation
and you're investing in the future for
yourself, for your family, for your
children, generations to come.
There's that thread
of knowledge that's where the money's
going to and what we're trying to
uh build in the back of it. Um and that
transparency of what we're doing. Um
that should give everyone pride in
investing. Every time they pay the
premium, they should feel I know where
it's going. I know it will help the
society I I'm part of. That would be key
for me.
Excellent. Thank you, Conor. And lastly,
over to Kevin, the CEO. Yeah, so I I
echo what Conor said.
So, I have nothing more to say.
Your team has done the job.
>> Yeah. Um
I'll say this.
Believe in the values that Prudential as
an organization believes in.
Because it's all about us, management
team and employees making right
decisions every day.
Whether it be making investments whether
it be building the right distribution,
whether it be building the right
product, providing the right service.
Um that's the starting point.
So, when you're choosing a solution,
whatever it may be, always see the brand
and the people behind the brand to see
if they're actually making the right
decision for the customers.
Very good. We are ahead of time. We have
about 10 minutes left. So, one last
question for all three of you. I ask
this for all of my podcast guests, all
363 that I've had on the podcast last
few years. Which is we have you on stage
here today to share your expertise about
the future of these insurance products,
the industry, and of course, Vietnam and
its customers.
Uh but we have all these wonderful
wonderful people in the room here today.
Uh what's something that you guys would
like to learn more about so that someone
here could help answer for you?
And to do your job better. So, Manish,
we'll start with you. Doesn't have to be
a person. It could be anything that
you're curious about to do your job just
a little bit better for Vietnam.
>> So, what would we like to learn about?
>> learn from the audience.
>> Yes. Okay. Well, I'd love to learn
um
how you filter
everything that's happening, has has
happened in the industry in the last few
months or last couple of years
to then considering the innovation, the
new products that are coming in
and how do you sort of segregate the
two? And how can therefore we customize
and we build better journeys and better
propositions
so that we can really really focus on
rebuilding that trust
and filling the gap that exists in the
market. So, I'd really like to
understand the mindset
on how you sort of distinguish between
what's happened in the past and how
you're looking at the future. Because
that's quite key insight for us.
Excellent. Conor, over to you.
Um I would come back probably to
elements of the protection, protection
gap. Primarily is
you know, this is a question to our
partners and to our distributors is what
are we not covering that a customer
holds dear?
How can we get a product
to fill a need that's there that we're
not seeing
as a company.
Um
You know, the government's got an You
know, the it's great the government have
got a will to double the amount of
people who are covered
within the country over the next uh 5
years
uh to go over 20 million
um
of the population.
The question is from kind of coming from
the demand side. It's easy for us to sit
back and create a product that we think
will work.
But I'm very keen to understand from our
distributors and our partners
what the customers want and how can we
meet match that need
a bit more. So, there's a very key piece
of getting that dialogue going and
making sure that we're learning enough
uh from the customer base and and and
and fill that gap. You know, the gap is
real. Um there's too many families pay
too much money for protection, for
health. Um we think we're in a position
to fulfill that.
How can we step into that gap?
Amazing. Love it. And Kevin, over to
you. I I don't see them as our partners,
but I see them as our prospects.
What will give them the peace of mind?
That's what I would want to understand
um individually because they all have a
different
uh I guess aspirations, needs.
Yeah.
Thank you so much to Kevin, Conor, and
Manish, uh the leadership team of
Prudential Vietnam. I'll see you guys
next time.
[Music]